[
    {
        "question": "1. (201) What voltage classes can be used for a Distribution System?",
        "options": [
            "a. 5 kilovolts (kV), 15 kV, and 25 kV.",
            "b. 5 kV, 15 kV, 20 kV and 25 kV.",
            "c. 5 kV, 15 kV, 20 kV, and 35 kV.",
            "d. 5 kV, 15 kV, 25 kV, and 35 kV."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 5 kV, 15 kV, 25 kV, and 35 kV."
    },
    {
        "question": "2. (202) The main substation is usually located as close as possible to ",
        "options": [
            "a. the center of the base load distribution.",
            "b. the geographic center of the base.",
            "c. the command post.",
            "d. base operations."
        ],
        "correct": "a. the center of the base load distribution."
    },
    {
        "question": "3. (202) Which item is designed to open a circuit automatically under load and then restore the service quickly once the fault has cleared?",
        "options": [
            "a. Fused cutout.",
            "b. Sectionalizer.",
            "c. Circuit breaker.",
            "d. Pole-top switch."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Circuit breaker."
    },
    {
        "question": "4. (202) A substation with one incoming transmission circuit and three outgoing distribution circuits has (at least) how many lightning arresters?",
        "options": [
            "a. 4.",
            "b. 8.",
            "c. 12.",
            "d. 16."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 12."
    },
    {
        "question": "5. (202) Which item supplies control voltage to operate circuit breakers?",
        "options": [
            "a. Batteries.",
            "b. Signal generators.",
            "c. Current transformers.",
            "d. Distribution transformers."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Batteries."
    },
    {
        "question": "6. (203) In a circuit, the step-voltage regulator's primary and secondary windings are configured with the primary in ",
        "options": [
            "a. series and the secondary in series.",
            "b. parallel and the secondary in series.",
            "c. series and the secondary in parallel.",
            "d. parallel and the secondary in parallel."
        ],
        "correct": "b. parallel and the secondary in series."
    },
    {
        "question": "7. (204) What item in an oil circuit breaker suppresses an arc? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Oil.",
            "b. Dashpot.",
            "c. Protective relay.",
            "d. Current transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Oil."
    },
    {
        "question": "8. (204) What oil circuit breaker components supply amperage to the protective relays?",
        "options": [
            "a. Timer ports.",
            "b. Main contacts.",
            "c. Terminal bushings.",
            "d. Current transformers."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Current transformers."
    },
    {
        "question": "9. (204) The insulating quality of sulfur hexafluoride (SF6), at 0 PSI, is how much greater than dry air? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 2½ times.",
            "b. 4 times.",
            "c. 6½ times.",
            "d. 8 times."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 2½ times."
    },
    {
        "question": "10. (205) Why are high-voltage fuses enclosed? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Aids with heat dissipation.",
            "b. Allows for more current flow.",
            "c. Reduces noise, gas or smoke due to a short circuit.",
             "d. To keep melted metal from dropping into nearby equipment."
        ],
        "correct": "d. To keep melted metal from dropping into nearby equipment."
    },
    {
        "question": "11. (205) What is installed inside the insulated fiberglass tube assembly to complete the connection between the upper and lower contacts on the fuse holder? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Door.",
            "b. Fuse link.",
            "c. Fuse-tube.",
            "d. Fuse cutout."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Fuse link."
    },
    {
        "question": "12. (205) How can a craftsmen easy identify blown fuse cutout? ",
        "options": [
            "a. The tail is up.",
            "b. Fuse link is closed.",
            "c. A cutout door is hanging down.",
            "d. Stinger wire is hanging from stirrup."
        ],
        "correct": "c. A cutout door is hanging down."
    },
    {
        "question": "13. (206) What percent of electrical system faults are temporary? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 25.",
            "b. 55.",
            "c. 75.",
            "d. 95."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 95."
    },
    {
        "question": "14. (206) Which of these devices does not interrupt a fault current? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Fused cutout.",
            "b. Sectionalizer.",
            "c. Oil circuit breaker.",
            "d. Oil circuit recloser."
        ],
        "correct": "b. Sectionalizer."
    },
    {
        "question": "15. (207) Where are overhead switches normally mounted?",
        "options": [
            "a. Inside a fenced area.",
            "b. Underground vaults.",
            "c. Inside metal enclosures.",
            "d. On substation structures or utility poles."
        ],
        "correct": "d. On substation structures or utility poles."
    },
    {
        "question": "16. (207) What is required for a gang operated overhead switch on a 3-phase circuit?",
        "options": [
            "a. One set of contacts.",
            "b. Three sets of blades.",
            "c. One set of blades and contacts.",
            "d. Three sets of blades and contacts."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Three sets of blades and contacts."
    },
    {
        "question": "17. (208) What is usually installed with an oil circuit breaker to allow for equipment maintenance and allows you to keep the circuit in operation?",
        "options": [
            "a. Fused cutouts.",
            "b. Circuit breakers.",
            "c. Fused cutouts and a backup oil circuit recloser. d. Knife blades and a normally open air-break switch."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Knife blades and a normally open air-break switch."
    },
    {
        "question": "18. (209) The oil in oil circuit breakers is checked dielectrically .",
        "options": [
            "a. every month.",
            "b. every 3 months.",
            "c. every 6 months.",
            "d. once a year."
        ],
        "correct": "c. every 6 months."
    },
    {
        "question": "19. (209) Strong odor from the gas in a sulfur hexaflouride circuit breaker is an indication that",
        "options": [
            "a. breaker load is too high.",
            "b. gas pressure is too high.",
             "c. gas decomposition has taken place.",
            "d. insulation breakdown has taken place."
        ],
        "correct": "c. gas decomposition has taken place."
    },
    {
        "question": "20. (209) Clean a modern air switch that has been closed for a long time by ",
        "options": [
            "a. sanding lightly with emery cloth.",
            "b. using wire wool and silicon grease.",
            "c. using a clean cloth and a wire brush.",
            "d. opening and closing the switch several times."
        ],
        "correct": "d. opening and closing the switch several times."
    },
    {
        "question": "21. (210) Battery bank maintenance is normally done",
        "options": [
            "a. every month.",
            "b. every 6 months.",
            "c. once a year.",
            "d. every 5 years."
        ],
        "correct": "a. every month."
    },
    {
        "question": "22. (210) What is used to test a battery cell for its specific gravity?",
        "options": [
            "a. Litmus paper.",
            "b. Barometric gauge.",
            "c. Colormetric chart.",
            "d. Hydrometer syringe."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Hydrometer syringe."
    },
    {
        "question": "23. (211) Switchboard graphic instruments and revenue watt-hour meters must be calibrated every ",
        "options": [
            "a. year.",
            "b. 2 years.",
            "c. 3 years.",
            "d. 4 years."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 4 years."
    },
    {
        "question": "24. (212) Which device is essentially a voltage regulator and requires similar servicing?",
        "options": [
            "a. Air-break switch.",
            "b. Overcurrent relay.",
            "c. Oil circuit breaker.",
            "d. Distribution transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Distribution transformer."
    },
    {
        "question": "25. (212) The maintenance interval for voltage regulators is every",
        "options": [
            "a. month.",
            "b. 6 months.",
            "c. year.",
            "d. 5 years."
        ],
        "correct": "c. year."
    },
    {
        "question": "26. (213) Battery electrolyte impurities cause",
        "options": [
            "a. irregular cell operation.",
            "b. low specific gravity reading.",
            "c. high specific gravity reading.",
            "d. extremely high gassing of the battery."
        ],
        "correct": "a. irregular cell operation."
    },
    {
        "question": "27. (213) After repair work on a relay you must ",
        "options": [
            "a. notify electrical supervisor.",
            "b. make a relay dielectric test.",
            "c. make a complete performance test.",
            "d. match the tap block setting with other relays."
        ],
        "correct": "c. make a complete performance test."
    },
    {
        "question": "28. (214) What publication outlines how to perform a flash hazard analysis to determine personal protective equipment requirement?",
        "options": [
            "a. Unified Facilities Criteria (UFC) 3-570-06.",
            "b. The Linemen's and Cablemen's Handbook.",
            "c. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70 E.",
            "d. NFPA 72."
        ],
        "correct": "c. National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 70 E."
    },
    {
        "question": "29. (215) Leather protectors or gauntlets should be ",
        "options": [
            "a. the same length as the rubber gloves.",
            "b. 4 inches longer than the rubber gloves.",
            "c. 1 to 3 inches longer than the rubber gloves.",
            "d. 2 to 5 inches shorter than the rubber gloves."
        ],
        "correct": "d. 2 to 5 inches shorter than the rubber gloves."
    },
    {
        "question": "30. (215) Which of these combinations are you likely to use inside rubber gloves?",
        "options": [
            "a. Nylon gloves and hand cream.",
            "b. Cotton gloves and hand cream.",
            "c. Nylon gloves and dusting powder.",
            "d. Cotton gloves and dusting powder."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Cotton gloves and dusting powder."
    },
    {
        "question": "31. (216) The supervisor must visually inspect rubber blankets every ",
        "options": [
            "a. week.",
            "b. month.",
            "c. 6 months.",
            "d. year."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 6 months."
    },
    {
        "question": "32. (216) How must rubber blankets be stored?",
        "options": [
            "a. Rolled up and taped.",
            "b. In a designated truck bin.",
             "c. Flat or rolled in blanket canister.",
            "d. Folded and placed in a canvas bag."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Flat or rolled in blanket canister."
    },
    {
        "question": "33. (216) While working, what must be done if your rubber gloves come in contact with petroleum based products?",
        "options": [
            "a. Wipe them off quickly.",
            "b. Wash them with mild soap and water.",
            "c. Stop work and perform immediate di-electric test. d. Continue working, petroleum products will have no effect on rubber."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Wipe them off quickly."
    },
    {
        "question": "34. (216) While inspecting rubber insulating line hoses, which condition would require the line hose to be removed from service? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Damage extending ¼ of the wall thickness.",
            "b. Damage extending ¼ inch in length.",
            "c. Damage extending ¼ inch in depth.",
            "d. Any signs of mechanical damage."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Damage extending ¼ of the wall thickness."
    },
    {
        "question": "35. (217) What is used to clean nylon parts of body work positioning equipment? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Laundry detergent and a soft bristle brush.",
            "b. Saddle soap and water.",
            "c. Mild soap and water.",
            "d. Neat's foot oil."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Mild soap and water."
    },
    {
        "question": "36. (217) When leather cannot be made soft and pliable enough by saddle-soap dressing, it should be",
        "options": [
            "a. oiled.",
            "b. discarded.",
            "c. weight tested.",
            "d. inspected for dry rot."
        ],
        "correct": "a. oiled."
    },
    {
        "question": "37. (218) Which part of the gaff do you sharpen? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Top ridge.",
            "b. Outer ridge.",
            "c. Rounded edge.",
            "d. Flat inner side."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Flat inner side."
    },
    {
        "question": "38. (219) How should you plan your climbing route with respect to a single crossarm?",
        "options": [
            "a. Opposite the crossarm.",
            "b. Same side as the crossarm.",
            "c. To the left of the crossarm.",
            "d. To the right of the crossarm."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Opposite the crossarm."
    },
    {
        "question": "39. (219) When two workers are ascending a pole, the second worker must not start climbing until ",
        "options": [
            "a. the first one is on the ground.",
            "b. the first one is in a safe work position.",
            "c. the second one is in a safe work position.",
            "d. the second one is directly below the first."
        ],
        "correct": "b. the first one is in a safe work position."
    },
    {
        "question": "40. (220) Which of the following manufacturer's certification tests is acceptable for hotsticks?",
        "options": [
            "a. 75,000 volts alternating current (AC) per foot for 5 minutes on fiberglass and epoxy sticks.",
            "b. 75,000 volts direct current (DC) per foot for 5 minutes on fiberglass and epoxy sticks.",
            "c. 100,000 volts AC per foot for 5 minutes on fiberglass and epoxy sticks.",
            "d. 100,000 volts DC per foot for 5 minutes on fiberglass and epoxy sticks."
        ],
        "correct": "c. 100,000 volts AC per foot for 5 minutes on fiberglass and epoxy sticks."
    },
    {
        "question": "41. (221) Hot sticks are electrically tested with a",
        "options": [
            "a. megger.",
            "b. voltmeter.",
            "c. direct current (DC) hi-pot test set.",
            "d. high-voltage phasing tool."
        ],
        "correct": "c. direct current (DC) hi-pot test set."
    },
    {
        "question": "42. (221) How long is the 100-kilovolts (kV) test voltage applied to a hot stick? ",
        "options": [
            "a. 1 minute.",
            "b. 2 minutes.",
            "c. 3 minutes.",
            "d. 4 minutes."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 1 minute."
    },
    {
        "question": "43. (222) At the job site, the aerial lift device should be positioned so the work area is always",
        "options": [
            "a. in front of the truck.",
            "b. directly over the truck.",
            "c. within reach of the boom.",
             "d. to the right side of the operator."
        ],
        "correct": "c. within reach of the boom."
    },
    {
        "question": "44. (222) Materials or tools can only be passed from a worker on the ground to a worker on the aerial lift vehicle when ",
        "options": [
            "a. both workers are wearing rubber gloves.",
            "b. the worker on the ground is wearing rubber gloves.",
            "c. the worker on the vehicle is wearing rubber gloves.",
            "d. the worker on the ground stands on an insulated stool."
        ],
        "correct": "a. both workers are wearing rubber gloves."
    },
    {
        "question": "45. (223) The test voltage for an aerial lift basket test is ",
        "options": [
            "a. 100 kilovolts (kV) direct current (DC).",
            "b. 125 kV DC.",
            "c. 150 kV DC.",
            "d. 200 kV DC."
        ],
        "correct": "a. 100 kilovolts (kV) direct current (DC)."
    },
    {
        "question": "46. (224) The line truck winch is operated",
        "options": [
            "a. through the transfer case.",
             "b. through the power takeoff.",
            "c. from direct drive through the engine.",
            "d. from the engine through the back transmission."
        ],
        "correct": "b. through the power takeoff"
    },
    {
        "question": "47. (224) How is the rope put on the capstan?",
        "options": [
            "a. Thread it from top to bottom, with the load toward the front of the truck.",
            "b. Thread it from bottom to top, with the load end away from the truck.",
            "c. Wind it counterclockwise, with the load toward the rear of the truck.",
            "d. Wind it clockwise, with the load end next to the truck."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Wind it clockwise, with the load end next to the truck."
    },
    {
        "question": "48. (225) The purpose of hand signals is to ensure",
        "options": [
            "a. proper installation of poles.",
            "b. clear communication between linemen and ground worker.",
            "c. proper understanding between supervisor and subordinates.",
            "d. clear communication between truck operator and ground worker."
        ],
        "correct": "d. clear communication between truck operator and ground worker."
    },
    {
        "question": "49. (225) What does holding up a closed fist indicate? ",
        "options": [
            "a. Lift pole.",
            "b. Winch up.",
            "c. Raise boom.",
            "d. Stop all action."
        ],
        "correct": "d. Stop all action."
    },
    {
        "question": "50. (226) Which of these is the Operator's Inspection Guide and Trouble Report (Aircraft Towing, Base Maintenance, Deicers, High Reach and Snow Removal), on which you write up line truck inspection discrepancies?",
        "options": [
            "a. AF Form 373.",
            "b. AF Form 374.",
            "c. AF Form 1800.",
            "d. AF Form 1806."
        ],
        "correct": "c. AF Form 1800."
    },
    {
        "question": "51. (227) What is the more common name for a constant current transformer?",
        "options": [
            "a. Power transformer.",
            "b. Distribution transformer.",
             "c. Constant current regulator.",
            "d. Instrumentation transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "c. Constant current regulator."
    },
    {
        "question": "52. (228) The insulation value of transformer coils, bushings, and oil determines ",
        "options": [
            "a. the power that the transformer can handle.",
            "b. the current capacity of the transformer.",
            "c. the voltage rating of the transformer.",
            "d. the size of the transformer."
        ],
        "correct": "c. the voltage rating of the transformer."
    },
    {
        "question": "53. (229) When you make a delta-delta connection for lights and power, there is one unusable voltage from ",
        "options": [
            "a. A phase to B phase.",
            "b. B phase to neutral.",
            "c. B phase to C phase.",
            "d. C phase to A phase."
        ],
        "correct": "b. B phase to neutral."
    },
    {
        "question": "54. (230) Which meter do you use in a transformer continuity check?",
        "options": [
            "a. Megger.",
            "b. Voltmeter.",
            "c. Ohmmeter.",
            "d. Clamp-on ammeter."
        ],
        "correct": "a. Megger."
    },
    {
        "question": "55. (230) Which connection would you use for a continuity check on the primary winding of a transformer? ",
        "options": [
            "a. H1 to H2.",
            "b. X1 to X3.",
            "c. H1 to X3.",
            "d. H2 to case."
        ],
        "correct": "a. H1 to H2."
    }
]